Edward Monbiot

DATA SCIENTIST

Ex-Financial Technology professional transitioning into a Data Scientist role after completing a master's degree at Barcelona School of Economics. More than six years of experience working in hedge fund and electronic trading institutions. Core skills include extrapolating data and providing actionable insights applied to achieve project goals.

EDUCATION

DATA SCIENCE FOR DECISION MAKING

MSc, Barcelona School of Economics, Spain September 2023 – July 2024

Relevant Data Science Projects:

- ✓ Machine Learning: FIFA 2022 Classification Model to Predict Youth Football Player Positions
- ✓ Text Mining & NLP: Research the Impact of Barcelona Festivals on Booking.com Hotel Prices

MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

BEng (Grade 2.1), Trinity College Dublin, Ireland September 2011 – June 2015

WORK EXPERIENCE

CAXTON ASSOCIATES Macro Hedge fund, \$10 Billion AUM

London, UK March 2019 - June 2023

Trading Support Engineer

Responsible for the smooth operation of critical trade capture systems. Worked with traders to resolve time sensitive production issues. Developed automated alerts and monitoring dashboards to anticipate data irregularities. In charge of platform demonstrations and user access permissions. Also worked on a three-year company-wide project to upgrade firm's trading infrastructure system.

TRAIANA Post-Trade Fintech Firm, Servicing 2100+ Clients London, UK September 2016 – March 2019

Project Manager

Delivered more than 100 projects for hedge fund clients. Worked with Sales to secure new customers, extensive project UAT, corrected product bugs, guided clients through project bottlenecks and provided go-live support. Prior role was covering the helpdesk, resolving urgent client issues covering a range of financial instruments.

CONTACT

Barcelona, Spain Mobile: +34 610193789

Email: monbiote@gmail.com
https://github.com/monbiote
https://www.linkedin.com/in/edwar
d-monbiot-609047a6/

NATIONALITY

British & Filipino

SKILLS

Data & Cloud Computing Tools

- Python (Pandas, NumPy, SK Learn, Matplotlib, Seaborn, NLTK, Beautiful Soup)
- R
- Databases (MySQL)
- AWS

Techniques

- Machine Learning
- Text Mining
- Natural Language Processing
- Unit Testing
- Hypothesis Testing

Foreign Languages:

Spanish (intermediate)

VOLUNTEERING

Fundación Social Antorches de Vida, (June – July 2016) Medellín, Colombia. English & Maths Teacher

OTHER INTERESTS

Tennis: played competitively on the UK junior circuit, captained high school (2011) and university 1st teams (2015)

Chess, padel, kitesurfing, skiing